<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>MacOS Fingerprint in bash</title>
    <link href="/2022/12/30/2023/MacOS-Fingerprint-in-bash/"/>
    <url>/2022/12/30/2023/MacOS-Fingerprint-in-bash/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First, open up Terminal. Navigate to the directory where the system stores the list of PAMs by typing <code>cd /etc/pam.d/</code> and open the <code>sudo</code> file there in your favorite command-line text editor.</p><span id="more"></span><p>1 (You can also always use a GUI editor like BBEdit too.) Note that if you open it via the command-line, you’ll need to use <code>sudo</code> itself to do so, since the file is (understandably) protected.</p><p>Once you’ve opened it, add the following below the first line (you’ll see the headers under which each of the entries goes):</p><blockquote><p><code>auth sufficient pam_tid.so</code></p></blockquote><p>That line basically tells the <code>sudo</code> command that the Touch ID authentication module is sufficient to authorize the user, which is all you need to do.</p><p><img src="https://cubox.pro/c/filters:no_upscale(" alt="Sudo with Touch ID">?imageUrl=https%3A%2F%2Fi0.wp.com%2Fsixcolors.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2020%2F11%2Fsudo-touchid.png%3Fssl%3D1)</p><p>Save the file and you’re done! Now, the next time you use the <code>sudo</code> command, instead of being prompted for your password, you’ll get a dialog box asking you to authenticate with Touch ID, just as you would any other time you needed to authenticate. (And, as an extra bonus, if you choose to click the Enter Password, you’ll get prompted to use either the password <em>or</em> your Apple Watch, if you have one.)</p><ol><li>I’m going to forestall the <code>vi</code> versus <code>emacs</code> debate by saying I’m a <code>pico</code>/<code>nano</code> guy, don’t @ me. ↩</li></ol><p><a href="https://sixcolors.com/post/2020/11/quick-tip-enable-touch-id-for-sudo/">查看原网页: sixcolors.com</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Skill</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>MacOS</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
